{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
      "options": [
        "Hyper Text Markup Language",
        "High Tech Modern Language",
        "Hyperlink and Text Manipulation Language",
        "Home Tool Markup Language"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Hyper Text Markup Language"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML element is used to define the structure of an HTML document?",
      "options": [
        "<structure>",
        "<body>",
        "<html>",
        "<format>"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "<html>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the correct HTML tag for creating an unordered list?",
      "options": [
        "<ol>",
        "<dl>",
        "<ul>",
        "<li>"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "<ul>"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML element is used for creating hyperlinks?",
      "options": [
        "<link>",
        "<a>",
        "<hlink>",
        "<url>"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "<a>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the HTML <head> element?",
      "options": [
        "To define the main content of the web page.",
        "To define the header section of the web page.",
        "To specify the metadata of the web page.",
        "To create a hyperlink."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "To specify the metadata of the web page."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML tag is used to insert a line break within a paragraph?",
      "options": [
        "<br>",
        "<lb>",
        "<newline>",
        "<break>"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "<br>"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which attribute is used to specify the alternative text for an image in HTML?",
      "options": [
        "alt",
        "title",
        "image-text",
        "description"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "alt"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the HTML <form> element?",
      "options": [
        "To create a table.",
        "To define a section of the web page.",
        "To create a navigation menu.",
        "To create a user input form."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "To create a user input form."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML tag is used to define a table row?",
      "options": [
        "<tr>",
        "<td>",
        "<th>",
        "<table-row>"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "<tr>"
    },
    {
      "question": "In HTML, which tag is used to create a clickable button?",
      "options": [
        "<button>",
        "<input type=\"button\">",
        "<clickable>",
        "<link>"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "<input type=\"button\">"
    }
  ]
}
